John Croker

Software Engineer

+44 7462 286764 jj.croker@gmail.com johncroker.me https:

https://github.com/johnjoey

Personal Statement

I am a software engineer with 5 years of experience developing applications for various industries. I have worked on many projects from design to completion, as well as maintaining and upgrading legacy systems. I strive to balance high standards, while also delivering robust code in a timely fashion. In my next place of work I am looking for a team of several engineers with a strong culture of personal growth and constructive criticism that uses modern technologies and practices.

Skills

Programming Languages

JavaScript(es7), Sass/LESS/CSS(BEM), HTML, PHP(5.x - 7.x+), MySQL

Libraries and Frameworks

Vue/Vuex, AngularJS, React, Redux, Laravel, Zend, Slim

Tooling

Docker, Ansible, Webpack, Babel, Gulp, PHPUnit, Jira, Git, Bitbucket

Experience

Software Engineer @ Magma Digital Ltd.

October 2019 - Present

Magma being an agency has exposed me to a variety of challenges - from maintaining legacy systems, liaising with clients and taking new projects from concept to completion. Some notable accomplishments include:

- Development on a health and risk assessment application for a large, multi-national company. Ingrained as part of the team, introducing new features to product owner specification
- Built a feature for synchronising data between multiple legacy freight applications
- Operated on a support basis, working directly with a client to estimate and prioritise support issues, and breaking down requirements for new feature work
- Worked with client's in-house developers on an API to facilitate large new features for the application to consume
- Managed multiple clients directly with a flexible approach to suit their work style and expectations, while implementing agile work practices like sprint planning where possible
- Mentored students as part of 12 week PHP coding bootcamp

Web Developer @ Barcadia Media

2015 - 2019

- Designed and developed brochure and CMS applications in collaboration with design team
- ▶ Updated legacy code to use modern frameworks such as Vue/Vuex and Laravel
- Led our team in adopting more Agile work practices like source control, sprint planning and daily stand-ups
- Mentored new hire and educated peers in the use of common design patterns and practices

Freelance Web Developer

2014 - 2015

- Created WordPress plugins for a company CMS
- ▶ Front-end development on WordPress websites

Education

Lancaster University (2011 - 2014)
BSc (Hons) in Computer Science - First Class Honours

Blackpool and Fylde College (2009 - 2011)

IT Practitioner BTEC Diploma (Distinction)

References

Jeremy Coates - CEO @ Magma Digital Ltd

hello+ref@phpcodemonkey.me.uk

Andy Shields - Director @ Barcadia Media Ltd

- andy@barcadiamedia.co.uk
- ▷ 01253 272998